Tham Yik Foong

Location: Fukuoka, Japan | Nationality: Malaysian | Github: https://github.com/zfoong

Telephone: +81 80 4940 8203 | Website: https://zfoong.github.io

Google Scholar: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=Q24NWS4AAAAJ

Email: Tham yikfoong@outlook.com | University email: tham.yik.foong.256@s.kyushu-u.ac.jp



Profile Summary

Currently a Ph.D. student at Laboratory of Intelligent Systems, Kyushu University, with research interests lie in Reinforcement Learning, Intelligent Agent System, Neural Network and Reservoir Computing. Contain experience as a software engineer and have acquired knowledge of product manufacturing and software architecture design. Committed to professional development and continuous learning in the field of AI, while also having a genuine interest in artificial general intelligence. Currently looking to fill a position as an assistant professor.

Academic Training

PhD	Artificial	Intelligence

Laboratory of Intelligent Systems, Kyushu University (2021 – 2024 Oct)

Supervised by Dr Danilo Vasconcellos Vargas

MSc Machine learning in Science

University of Nottingham (2019 - 2020)

With Distinction

BSc (Hons) Bachelor of Software Engineering with Multimedia

Limkokwing University (2015 – 2017)

CGPA: 3.9/4.0 (First Class)

Career Summary

Dec 2020 – Jun 2021 Teacher/Al Instructor (Contract)
ORBIX International Schools/Al Academy

Outline

Create lesson plans and teach in PE, AI, and Computer Science for Year 2 to Year 11 students. Other duties involved creating teaching materials in collaboration with iFLYTEK AI, curriculum development and planning, and managing campus IT infrastructure. This role was a contract job, undertaken to acquire teaching experience and to fill the gap during the Covid-19 outbreak before commencing my PhD.

Key Responsibilities

- Develop and deliver lesson plans, curriculums and teaching materials.
- Manage campus IT systems, address technical issues, and ensure optimal functionality.
- Engage with students, parents, and iFLYTEK AI to support learning and student admissions.

Mar 2018 – July 2019 Software Engineer (ATTD Department) Intel

Outline

Develop station controller (machine controller) that communicates with equipment and backend system, controlling the business flow of product manufacturing. This position required knowledge of object-oriented programming and design pattern, understanding the business process of product manufacturing, communication skill as this position work closely with individuals from different factory sites across different countries.

Key Responsibilities

- Develop station controller in C# and gather requirements from tech lead and customer (module integrator)
- Testing station controller to ensure it runs smoothly in production environment
- Provide code level technical support
- Assigned to compose a station controller development guide and provide coaching for peer and new hire

July 2017 – Sept 2017 Tutor (6 Sessions) MY EDVENTURE

Outline

As a tutor of MyEdventure coding Bootcamp, teaching subject includes HTML, CSS, Javascript.

Key Responsibilities

- Prepare teaching material
- Teaching and provide guidance

Jun 2017 – Sept 2017 Web Developer Intern TIME.COM

Outline

Design and develop webpages for one of the major ISP in Malaysia.

Key Responsibilities

 Design and develop webpages, company internal web tool, online survey form using HTML, CSS, Javascript and PHP

Grants

SPRING Integrated Research Project for FY2023, "Intelligent Agent-Driven Active Brownian Particles: Self-Organization and Dynamics of Collective and Vortical Motion", Award amount: 500,000¥.

JST SPRING, Research Aid, Award amount: 200,000¥ per month, April 2022 – present.

ASEAN Masters Scholarship, September 2019 – September 2020

Awards

Travel Grant for CogSci 2023, Award amount: 178,000¥

Best Presentation Award, 2022 5th Artificial Intelligence and Cloud Computing Conference, for Tham Yik Foong: Understanding SyncMap: Analyzing the Components of its Dynamical Equation.

Publications

P Mao, Shashank, <u>TY Foong</u>, DV Vargas (2023): Synthetic Shifts to Initial Seed Vector exposes the Brittle Nature of Latent-Based Diffusion Models. Under review.

<u>TY Foong</u>, Shashank, P Mao, DV Vargas (2023): The Challenges of Image Generation Models in Generating Multi-Component Images. Under review.

<u>TY Foong</u>, DV Vargas (2023): Generating Oscillation Activity with Echo State Network to Mimic the Behavior of a Simple Central Pattern Generator. *In Proceedings of the Annual Meeting of the Cognitive Science Society, volume 45*. (Oral paper, 17% acceptance rate)

Video: https://youtu.be/Y46QJx1Fc0Q

Presentation: https://doi.org/10.48448/n2fz-wy85

P Mao, <u>Y Tham</u>, H Zhang, DV Vargas (2023): Magnum: Tackling high-dimensional structures with self-organization. In *Neurocomputing*, *volume 550*.

DV Vargas, <u>TY Foong</u>, H Zhang (2023): Dynamical Equations with Bottom-up Self-Organizing Properties Learn Accurate Dynamical Hierarchies Without Any Loss Function. Under review. Video: https://youtu.be/kWhTJG5XYmQ

<u>TY Foong</u>, DV Vargas (2022): Understanding SyncMap: Analyzing the components of Its Dynamical Equation. In *Proceedings of the 2022 5th Artificial Intelligence and Cloud Computing*. (Best Presentation Award)

<u>TY Foong</u>, DV Vargas (2021): Towards Learning Hierarchical Structures with SyncMap. In *2021 5th IEEE International Conference on Cybernetics (CYBCONF)*.

<u>TY Foong</u>, T Oakes (2020): Master Thesis: Using Reinforcement Learning to model Collective and Adversarial Behaviours with Active Brownian Particles.

Blog: https://zfoong.github.io/blog/collective-x-adversarial-ams.html

Languages

English (IELTS overall marking: 7.0) • Bahasa Malay • Cantonese • Chinese • Japanese (N2)